Guide to the Records of Phi Beta Kappa, Beta Chapter (New York University) RG.39.175
New York University Archives
Records of Phi Beta Kappa, Beta Chapter (New York University)
1856-1977
New York University Archives
Phi Beta Kappa
RG.39.175
3 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
This collection contains minutes, membership lists and other records of the Phi Beta Kappa chapter at NYU. NYU's chapter of the national academic honor society was founded in 1858.
Arrangement
Arrangement varies by series.
The files are grouped into 3 series:
Missing Title
Minutes
Members
Publications
Scope and Contents
Records consists of minutes, chapter reports, membership lists, historical statements, manuals, and copies of the Key Reporter mainly from the years 1856-1977.
History of Phi Beta Kappa at New York University
Phi Beta Kappa is a national scholastic honorary fraternity that elects their members on the basis of scholastic achievement and good moral character. The Phi Beta Kappa chapter at NYU was founded in 1858 and is the 15th oldest in the country as well as the second oldest in New York State. The society at NYU held many conferences and discussions and published their own news magazine, The Key Reporter.
Sources:
Phi Beta Kappa, Reference File
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Membership lists.; Administrative reports.; New York (N.Y.).; Publications (documents); Minutes (administrative records); Greek letter societies |z United States.; New York University; Phi Beta Kappa. Beta of New York (New York University); Phi Beta Kappa
- Series I: Minutes
  - Phi Beta Kappa Minutes, 1858-1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Minutes, ca.1918-1933, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Minutes, 1934-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Minutes, 1945-1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Minutes, 1956-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Minutes: Washington Square College, 1927-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Minutes: Washington Square College, 1941-1946 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series II: Membership
  - Letter of Acquistion to NYU Archives, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Presidents of Beta Chapter, Letters of Receipt of Copies, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photocopies of Chapter Business, 1840-1849, 1881-1883 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Typed Handbook, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Eligibility, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Committee Report on Role and Qualifications, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chapter Code List, and Faculty Count - National, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chapter Reports, 1936-1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chapter Reports, 1960-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - United Chapters: Manuals, Revisions, Reports, 1925, 1927-1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Past Officers of Beta, 1856-1956 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Membership Eligibility, 1966-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - List of Membership (Faculty), 1961-1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Elected Members, 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Elected Members, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Elected Members, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Elected Members, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Elected Members, Initiation Ritual and Historical Statement, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Elected Members, 1957-1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Elected Members, "Spirit of Scholarship" Homer A. Watt, 1940-1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Elected Members, Faculty (1962), 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Historical Statements, 1927-1945 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Establishment of Beta Chapter: Washington Square, 1922-1927 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Revisted Historical Statement, Meaning of Key, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Initiation Ritual, Historical Statement (1953), 1943, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Addresses of Members (1927-1940), Presidents of Beta (1927-1958), Officers of Beta (1927-1945) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Members Washington Square, 1927-1946 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Elected Members, 1960-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Revised Constitution (1918), Ritual (1928), Chapter Manual (1938), 1918-1938 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Elected Members, 1926-1932 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Address - Elmer Ellsworth Brown (1933), Music for Beta (1939), Address - Dean William B. Baer (1942), 1933-1942 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Elected Members, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Elected Members, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Elected Members (1966-1967), Undergrad. Election Statistics (1939-1940, 1965-1966), undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Elected Members, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Elected Members, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Elected Members, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Induction Luncheon, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Elected Members, Letter for Centennial Year, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Elected Members, 1946, 1948-1959 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Elected Members, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Elected Members, 1935-1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Initiation Meeting, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Immediate Members, Faculty, 1932-1949 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Membership Lists and Elected, 1932-1952 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Deceased Member List (1922, 1929), Honor Roll List (1939), Membership Mailing List (1939), 1922-1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer's Receipts and Notes, 1892-1928 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Anniversary Meeting, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Anniversary Meeting (1952), Honorary Member (1953), 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Anniversary Meeting, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Anniversary Meeting, 1961-1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Letter of Dr. T.F. Jones, 1930-1933 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Visiting Scholar Program, 1964, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Visiting Scholar Program, 1968-1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Ritual of Initiation, Oath, Jewelry Order Form, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Dedication of Phi Beta Kappa Memorial (Williamsburg, VA), 1957 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Triennial Reports, 1940-1961 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Honorary Membership Policy, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Changes of Address, Orders: Cap & Gowns, Certificates, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Associated Chapters Chapter Inventory, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Series III: Publications
  - Constitution and By-Laws of United Chapters, 1938-1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Delegates Manual, 1934, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Delegates Manual, 1961, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Form of Initiation, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Handbook for New Members, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin - Triennial Council, 1904-1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Key Reporter, 1938-1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Music Sheets, Men's Choice Written for Beta, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 8)